Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：
是的，是的，船长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
Breaker, breaker,
outer perimeter
looks clear, over.
断路器、断路器、
外周长
看起来很清楚，结束。
Uh, Robert, Robert,
uh, Ronald, Ronald.
呃，罗伯特，罗伯特，
呃，罗纳德，罗纳德。
Ryan.
瑞安.
Are you sure you're not trying
to say Roger?
你确定你不尝试吗
说罗杰？
Patrick: Oh, wait,
I got it, I got it.
帕特里克：哦，等等，
我明白了，我明白了。
Ringo.
林戈。
Patrick, we have visual contact.
帕特里克，我们有视觉接触。
Now taking evasive action.
现在采取回避行动。
Subject still
in close proximity, over.
主题依然
近在咫尺，结束。
Hello?
你好？
Please reply.
请回复。
I wonder if I could order pizza
with this thing.
我想知道我是否可以订披萨
有了这个东西。
Please.
请。
Contact imminent, Patrick.
即将联系，帕特里克。
Respond now, please.
请立即回复。
Please.
请。
SpongeBob, you're gonna need
to speak up.
海绵宝宝，你需要
大声说出来。
My eardrums aren't what
they used to be.
我的耳膜不是这样的
他们曾经是。
I can't speak up, Patrick.
我不能说话，帕特里克。
There's a jellyfish over here,
and I'm worried it might
sting me if I make any loud...
这里有一只水母，
我担心它可能
如果我发出很大声就蜇我...
...noises.
...噪音。
Oops.
哎呀。
Is he still after us, Patrick?
他还在追我们吗，帕特里克？
I don't know, buddy.
我不知道，伙计。
Should we turn around and check?
我们应该回头检查一下吗？
Ok.
好的。
Ooh, I think I landed
on my pain center.
哦，我想我落地了
在我的疼痛中心。
I think I landed on a rock.
我想我落在了一块岩石上。
Patrick, look.
帕特里克，看。
There's a weird thing sticking
out of the ground right there.
有一个奇怪的东西粘在上面
从那里的地面上出来。
That's just Squidward
sunbathing again.
这只是章鱼哥
再次晒日光浴。
No, not that, Patrick.
不，不是那样，帕特里克。
This.
这。
What is it?
它是什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think there's something
buried underneath it
我认为有一些东西
埋在它下面
and I'm gonna
go get some shovels
so we can dig it up.
我会
去拿一些铲子
这样我们就可以把它挖出来。
We?
我们？
Nothing like a little
manual labor to put some hair
on your chest, eh, Patrick?
没什么像一点点
手工劳动来放置一些头发
在你胸前，呃，帕特里克？
I'll say.
我会说。
Plus, look at what
we unearthed: a U.F.O.
另外，看看什么
我们发现了：一个U.F.O.
Go on, you first.
继续吧，你先。
Kind of dark, huh?
有点黑暗吧？
Yeah, dark.
是的，黑暗。
Well, there's got to be
a light switch
around here somewhere.
嗯，一定有
一个电灯开关
就在这附近的某个地方。
Found it.
找到了。
Excuse me, sir.
对不起，先生。
Hey, Patrick, look.
嘿，帕特里克，看。
We're moving.
我们要搬家了。
And here's the steering wheel.
这是方向盘。
Oh, hold it, SpongeBob.
哦，坚持住，海绵宝宝。
You'd better let me drive.
你最好让我开车。
Give me that wheel.
把那个轮子给我。
No, let go.
不，放手吧。
I want to drive.
我想开车。
I don't understand, Squidward.
我不明白，章鱼哥。
Where are all the customers?
所有的顾客都在哪里？
I know the Krusty Krab
isn't Bikini Bottom's
most prestigious eatery
我认识蟹堡王
不是比基尼泳裤
最负盛名的餐馆
but at least it's better
than that salty old Chum Bucket
across the street
但至少这样更好
比那个咸的老密友桶
街对面
and that's our only competition.
这是我们唯一的竞争。
Am I getting paid extra
for this conversation?
我能得到额外报酬吗
为了这次谈话？
Come on, Squidward.
来吧，章鱼哥。
Can't you just pretend to listen
for once in your life?
你就不能假装在听吗
你一生中就一次吗？
Do it for old Mr. Krabs.
为老蟹老板做这件事吧。
well, since you can't
bring any customers
into the Krusty Krab
好吧，既然你不能
带来任何客户
进入蟹堡王
have you ever thought about
bringing the Krusty Krab
to the customers?
你有没有想过
带来了蟹堡王
给客户？
Quiet, Squidward,
I'm brainstorming.
安静，章鱼哥，
我正在集思广益。
Ooh, ooh.
哦哦。
What if,
instead of bringing customers
to the Krusty Krab
如果，
而不是带来顾客
到蟹堡王
we could bring the Krusty Krab
to the customers?
我们可以带Krusty Krab
给客户？
♪ La-la, la-la-la-la-la-la,
la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦，
啦啦啦啦♪
Why, yes, of course.
为什么，是的，当然。
But how?
但如何呢？
Can we park here?
我们可以在这里停车吗？
Hey, Mr. Krabs.
嘿，蟹老板。
Look what Patrick and I found.
看看帕特里克和我发现了什么。
We're gonna use it to go
on a long journey.
我们要用它去
在长途旅行中。
Or even around the block.
甚至在街区附近。
That's it.
就是这样。
We'll take the Krusty Krab
on the road.
我们要吃蟹堡王
在路上。
So long, lad.
再见，小伙子。
Make me lots of money.
让我赚很多钱。
Bye, Squidward.
再见，章鱼哥。
Bye, Mr. Krabs.
再见，蟹老板。
Bye, Squidward.
再见，章鱼哥。
You said "Bye, Squidward" twice.
你说了两次“再见，章鱼哥”。
I like Squidward.
我喜欢章鱼哥
A traveling restaurant, eh?
一家旅行餐厅，嗯？
It's not fair.
这不公平。
I had that idea years ago.
我几年前就有这个想法。
No matter.
不管。
If Mr. Krabs
wants to play dirty
如果蟹老板
想要玩肮脏的游戏
then Plankton's ready
for his turn to take his turn.
那么浮游生物就准备好了
轮到他了。
Hello.
你好。
Could I interest you
in a Krabby Patty?
我可以让你感兴趣吗
在蟹黄馅饼里？
No thanks.
不，谢谢。
Now what?
现在怎么办？
I don't know, Patrick.
我不知道，帕特里克。
Mr. Krabs said,
if we didn't find customers,
not to come back.
蟹老板说，
如果我们找不到客户
不回来。
Are you sure you don't want
to be our first customer, sir.
你确定你不想要
成为我们的第一个客户，先生。
Uh, yeah, I'm pretty sure.
呃，是的，我很确定。
SpongeBob: Wait.
海绵宝宝：等等。
We'll pay you.
我们会付钱给你。
Hey, thanks again, guys.
嘿，再次谢谢你们。
Good luck with the restaurant.
祝餐厅好运。
Thank you, sir.
谢谢您，先生。
Come again.
再来吧。
Those nincompoops are better
salesmen than I suspected.
那些傻瓜更好
推销员比我想象的还要多。
Woman: Customer approaching.
女：顾客来了。
Plankton: Hello, little boy.
浮游生物：你好，小男孩。
Would you like a chum burger?
您想要一个汉堡吗？
Uh, does it come in raspberry?
呃，有覆盆子色吗？
Uh, no.
呃，不。
Blueberry?
蓝莓？
No.
不。
Um... raspberry?
嗯...覆盆子？
Oh, come on, kid,
you asked me that already.
哦，来吧，孩子，
你已经问过我了。
Now quit wasting my time.
现在别再浪费我的时间了。
Hey, you can't talk
to my son that way.
嘿，你不能说话
对我儿子就是这样。
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁？
I'm Plankton, you old hag,
and your son
smells like boogers.
我是浮游生物，你这个老太婆，
和你的儿子
闻起来像鼻屎。
Hey, you can't talk
to my wife that way.
嘿，你不能说话
对我妻子来说就是这样。
What do you think this is?
你觉得这是什么？
I think it's time for you
to lose some weight, fattie.
我想你是时候了
减肥吧，胖子。
That's what it is.
就是这样。
Hey, you can't talk
to my grandson like that.
嘿，你不能说话
对我的孙子就是这样。
Someone ought to put you
in a mental hospital.
应该有人把你
在精神病院里。
Someone should put you
in a box floating
down the river, grandma.
应该有人把你
在一个漂浮的盒子里
奶奶，顺河而下。
You're probably right.
你可能是对的。
You people are crazy.
你们这些人太疯狂了。
I'm getting out of here.
我要离开这里。
What the?
什么？
No, controls malfunctioning.
不，控制装置出现故障。
Hey, Patrick?
嘿，帕特里克？
Yeah?
是的？
Weren't you supposed to be
on kitchen duty?
你不应该是
值班厨房？
Oh no, you burned
all the patties.
哦不，你烧伤了
所有的肉饼。
It's hard as a rock.
它像石头一样坚硬。
How're we gonna find
somebody who'll buy these?
我们要如何找到
有人会买这些吗？
Hey, the rocks are all gone.
嘿嘿，石头都不见了。
Aw.
噢。
Folks, have I got
a deal for you.
各位，我有吗
给你一笔交易。
All right, get him!
好吧，抓住他！
Won't Mr. Krabs be so proud
of us when he finds out
how good we're doing?
蟹老板会不会感到如此自豪
当他发现时我们
我们做得怎么样？
See any new customers, Patrick?
帕特里克，看到新顾客了吗？
No, but I see a sign.
不，但我看到一个标志。
It says, "Warning: ab eyes?"
它说：“警告：ab 眼睛？”
Here, let me see.
在这里，让我看看。
No, Patrick, that says "abyss."
不，帕特里克，那是“深渊”。
Patrick: Oh, ok.
帕特里克：哦，好吧。
What's an abyss, SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝，深渊是什么？
An abyss is a bottomless...
深渊是无底的...
...chasm!
...鸿沟！
Pat, we're falling!
帕特，我们正在坠落！
And now we're bathed in
an eerie red light!
现在我们沐浴在
诡异的红光！
Yes, yes!
是的，是的！
And now, a deafening
warning siren.
而现在，一声震耳欲聋的
警报器。
Look, Patrick.
看，帕特里克。
We floated back up out of
the deep, dark, depressing,
horrible abyss.
我们又浮了出来
深沉、黑暗、压抑，
可怕的深渊。
Who are you calling dark
and depressing?
你说谁黑暗
和郁闷？
We didn't mean it that way,
Mister Sea Monster, sir.
我们不是这个意思
海怪先生，先生。
Um, what we really want
to know is, are you hungry?
嗯，我们真正想要的
要知道的是，你饿了吗？
Hungry?
饥饿的？
I've been asleep for 79 years,
which means my last meal
was 79 years ago.
我已经睡了79年了
这意味着我的最后一顿饭
是79年前的事了。
Yes, I'm hungry.
是的，我饿了。
Well then, try one of
our Krabby Patties.
那么，尝试其中之一
我们的蟹肉饼。
Mm, that's the best thing
I've tasted since
that sewage spill back in '76.
嗯，这是最好的事情
我从那时起就尝过
76年的污水泄漏事件。
I'll take 640 of them.
我要 640 个。
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
Order up.
订购吧。
Now that those two
are out of the picture
现在那两个
不在画面中
all the customers'll
come running to me.
所有的顾客都会
跑到我身边来。
This calls
for "drasticerest" measures.
这调用
采取“最严厉”的措施。
Ok, you bums,
time for the second course.
好吧，你们这些流浪汉，
第二节课的时间到了。
Chum charges.
密友指控。
SpongeBob, our home's
been breached.
海绵宝宝，我们家
被破坏了。
You know what that means.
你知道那意味着什么。
No.
不。
Neither do I.
我也没有。
Yes!
是的！
I sunk the Krusty Krab.
我击沉了蟹堡王。
I sunk the... Oh!
我击沉了...哦！
Eh, who needs
that rustbucket anyhow?
呃，谁需要
无论如何，那个铁锈桶？
Come on in there.
进来吧。
I want more sandwiches.
我想要更多三明治。
SpongeBob, look.
海绵宝宝，看。
What is it?
它是什么？
It's a liquid.
它是一种液体。
SpongeBob: No, it's a solid,
it's a solid.
海绵宝宝：不，它是固体，
它是固体。
It's a "lol-squid."
这是一只“哈哈鱿鱼”。
All right, what's going
on in there?
好吧，发生什么事了
在那儿？
Hey, that looks like
a sandwich to me.
嘿，看起来像
给我一份三明治。
Not just a sandwich.
不仅仅是一个三明治。
It's a "chumwich."
这是一个“chumwich”。
Mm.
毫米。
Now that's a sandwich.
现在这是一个三明治。
Anything else
before we shell off?
还有什么吗
在我们脱壳之前？
I want dessert.
我想要甜点。
We don't have dessert.
我们没有甜点。
Don't give another penny
to those fast food phonies.
不要再给一分钱
对于那些快餐骗子。
That's right,
they stole my idea.
没错，
他们偷了我的想法。
My, my, my...
我的，我的，我的……
Hey, a chocolate eclair.
嘿，巧克力泡芙。
Now that looks like
dessert to me.
现在看起来像
甜点给我。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不，不，不，不。
You got it all wrong, see?
你全都搞错了，明白吗？
Here you are, Mr. Krabs.
给你，蟹老板。
Just like new again.
又像新的一样了。
Now all we got to do
is keep SpongeBob away from...
现在我们要做的就是
是让海绵宝宝远离...
We're back, Mr. Krabs.
我们回来了，蟹老板。
Tell me all about it.
告诉我一切。
Tell me, tell me, tell me,
tell me, tell me.
告诉我，告诉我，告诉我，
告诉我，告诉我。
You wouldn't believe it,
Mr. Krabs.
你不会相信，
蟹老板。
We had so many new customers.
我们有很多新客户。
I don't care about that.
我不在乎这个。
Tell me about the money.
告诉我关于钱的事。
There we were, at the bottom of
a deep, dark abyss, and we had
to let go of something heavy.
我们在那里，在底部
一个又深又暗的深渊，我们有
放下沉重的东西。
And paper.
还有纸。
You let go of all
the money I earned as ballast?
你放下一切
我当镇流器赚的钱？
But on the bright side,
we did manage to bring back
37,000 pounds
但从好的方面来看，
我们确实设法带回来了
37,000 磅
of these decorative
deep sea rocks.
这些装饰性的
深海岩石。
Where's your best friend
now, SpongeBob?
你最好的朋友在哪里
现在，海绵宝宝？
Well, according to this t-shirt,
it says my best friend
is right here.
嗯，根据这件 T 恤，
它说我最好的朋友
就在这里。
How about now?
现在怎么样？
Right by my side.
就在我身边。
Wow, clothing that announces
our feelings for each other.
哇，宣布的服装
我们对彼此的感情。
Let's get 'em, Patrick.
让我们抓住他们，帕特里克。
Can I help you, boys?
我可以帮助你们吗，孩子们？
I believe you can.
我相信你可以。
My best friend and I
would like to purchase...
我和我最好的朋友
想购买...
Patrick, why are you crying?
帕特里克，你为什么哭？
You found a new best friend.
你找到了一个新的最好的朋友。
Oh, what are you...?
噢，你是什么……？
Wait, no, this isn't
what it looks like.
等等，不，这不是
它看起来像什么。
Patrick, look out behind you.
帕特里克，小心你身后。
Excuse me,
but does this come in...
对不起，
但这是否进来...
No!
不！
You're not my best friend.
你不是我最好的朋友。
We got to ditch these outfits.
我们必须扔掉这些衣服。
They're sending out
the wrong signals.
他们正在发出
错误的信号。
We need new outfits to show
our best "friendiness," Pat.
我们需要新的服装来展示
我们最好的“友谊”，帕特。
You mean like those guys?
你是说像那些人一样？
Yeah, just like those guys.
是的，就像那些人一样。
Best friend outfits like these
really make a statement.
最好的朋友像这样的服装
真正发表声明。
Look at these guys.
看看这些家伙。
Whoa, I like that one.
哇哦，我喜欢那个。
Hey mister, where did you
and your friends get
your matching outfits?
嘿先生，你在哪里
你的朋友会得到
你的搭配服装？
Oh, no, these aren't my friends.
哦，不，这些不是我的朋友。
In fact, I hate
just about everyone here
其实我讨厌
几乎这里的每个人
but my love for historical
battles is so great
但我对历史的热爱
战斗是如此伟大
I join these losers
every year to reenact
the Battle of Bikini Bottom.
我加入这些失败者的行列
每年都会重演
比基尼堡之战。
There was a Battle
of Bikini Bottom?
有一场战斗
比基尼底部？
Well, duh, SpongeBob.
嗯，呃，海绵宝宝。
It's only the most significant
event in Bikini Bottom history.
这只是最重要的
比基尼泳裤历史上的事件。
A long time ago, the town
was divided into two groups
很久以前，这座小镇
被分成两组
those who spent all their time
washing their hands
like softies...
那些花费了全部时间的人
洗手
像软妹子一样...
Clean as a whistle.
干净如口哨。
Patrick: And those who had
more important things to do
with their time.
帕特里克：还有那些
更重要的事情要做
与他们的时间。
Well, looks good to me.
嗯，我觉得不错。
That is truly disgusting.
这实在是太恶心了。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
You can't go around
our town touching things
with those filthy mitts.
你不能四处走动
我们的小镇触动事物
带着那些肮脏的手套。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Yes.
是的。
Wash your hands.
洗手。
Never.
绝不。
And that's how we won our right
to wash as we please.
这就是我们赢得权利的方式
随心所欲地洗。
That's not what happened.
事实并非如此。
You don't wash
your hands, Patrick?
你不洗
你的手，帕特里克？
Never have, never will.
从来没有，也永远不会。
Blech.
布莱赫。
Does that bother you?
这让你烦恼吗？
Huh, SpongeBob?
哈，海绵宝宝？
They only had
one ice cream cone.
他们只有
一个蛋卷冰淇淋。
That's ok.
没关系。
Thank you, friend.
谢谢你，朋友。
So anyway, I said...
所以无论如何，我说...
Wait.
等待。
You got something
on your tongue.
你有东西
在你的舌头上。
Really?
真的吗？
Here, I'll get it.
在这里，我会得到它。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Frankly, yes, Patrick,
that does bother me.
坦率地说，是的，帕特里克，
这确实让我烦恼。
Well then I guess
we can't be friends.
那么我想
我们不能成为朋友。
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
Do I have to
spell it out for you?
我必须吗
给你拼出来吗？
You are... Um...
你是……嗯……
How do you spell
"not my friend?"
你怎么拼写
“不是我的朋友吗？”
Oh, come on.
哦，来吧。
We can work this out.
我们可以解决这个问题。
We'll start a new life.
我们将开始新的生活。
Just you, me, and this can
of disinfectant spray.
只有你、我，这可以
的消毒喷雾。
Come on in, Patrick.
进来吧，帕特里克。
Here, let me take
your coat for you.
在这里，让我带
你的外套给你。
No thank you.
不，谢谢。
I happen to like
my various smells and germs.
我恰好喜欢
我的各种气味和细菌。
But being clean
is so much better.
但保持干净
好多了。
Well, says you.
好吧，你说。
I like dirty.
我喜欢肮脏的。
Clean.
干净的。
Dirty.
肮脏的。
Clean.
干净的。
Uh, excuse us, but we have
a battle to reenact.
呃，对不起，但是我们有
一场重演的战斗。
Fine.
美好的。
If that's how it is, then
I am joining the other side.
如果是这样的话，那么
我加入了另一边。
Fine, me too.
好吧，我也是。
Oh, come on.
哦，来吧。
Let's go play somewhere else.
我们去别的地方玩吧。
Hah, got your nose.
哈哈，鼻子被摸到了
Hey, give it back.
嘿，还给我吧。
Not until you wash your hands.
直到你洗手为止。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Well, I got your eyeballs.
好吧，我抓住了你的眼球。
Huh?
啊？
Whoa.
哇哦。
Ew, brain juice.
呃，脑汁。
Do you give up yet?
你还放弃吗？
Sorry, Patrick,
but a filthy slob like you
对不起，帕特里克，
但像你这样的肮脏邋遢的人
is no match for
a clean-cut fellow like me.
不匹配
像我这样干净利落的人。
Your pants are falling down.
你的裤子快掉下来了
Really?
真的吗？
I'll fix it.
我会解决它。
Satisfied?
使满意？
There, you look good now.
在那里，你现在看起来很好。
You could use
a makeover, though.
你可以使用
不过，是一次改头换面。
Ugh, look at those feet.
呃，看看那双脚。
Why, what's wrong with them?
为什么，他们怎么了？
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I'll take care of it.
我会处理的。
No, not a pedicure.
不，不是修脚。
No, no, not that.
不，不，不是那样。
Anything but that.
除了那个之外什么都可以。
Not nail polish.
不是指甲油。
You sick little monster.
你这个病态的小怪物。
Face my morning breath.
面对我早晨的呼吸。
You, sir, could use
some dental hygiene?
先生，您可以使用
一些牙齿卫生？
Who, me?
谁，我？
My teeth are fine, see?
我的牙齿很好，看到了吗？
A little toothpaste,
and you'll have teeth like mine.
牙膏少许，
你将会拥有像我一样的牙齿。
You got to brush
in little circles.
你得刷
在小圈子里。
Minty fresh.
薄荷味清新。
Taste pit, evil-doer.
尝坑，恶人。
You're a stinky,
stinky sea star.
你就是个臭臭的
臭海星。
I think you could use
a shot of this.
我想你可以使用
一个镜头。
No, no, not, not deodorant.
不，不，不，不是除臭剂。
My beautiful pit-stink.
我美丽的坑臭。
It's gone.
它消失了。
The gloves are off now.
现在手套已经脱掉了。
It's booger time.
鼻屎时间到了。
Oh, booger "shmooger."
哦，鼻屎“shmooger”。
You don't even have a nose.
你连鼻子都没有。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Booger!
鼻屎！
Run!
跑步！
Run, Mr. Krabs.
快跑吧，蟹老板。
Patrick is digging for gold.
帕特里克正在挖金子。
Gold?
金子？
Did you get any
of Patrick's gold?
你收到了吗
帕特里克的黄金？
He's not digging for
any gold I'm looking for.
他不是在挖掘
我正在寻找的任何黄金。
Ah-ha.
啊哈。
I've got you now.
我现在已经得到你了。
Careful, Patrick.
小心，帕特里克。
I've got a weapon.
我有武器。
Ugh, raw onions.
呃，生洋葱。
That does it.
就可以了。
See this?
看到这个了吗？
A Krabby Patty?
蟹肉饼？
What are you gonna do, eat it?
吃掉你要做什么？
Oh, I'm not going to eat it.
哦，我不会吃它。
No, not patty socks.
不，不是小袜子。
That's right, your precious
patties on my stinky feet.
没错，你的宝贝
我的臭脚上有肉饼。
You better stop that.
你最好停止这种行为。
Stinky, little feet.
臭臭的，小脚。
Ooh, you stop that right now.
哦，你现在就停下来。
Hopping...
跳跃...
...crabs.
...螃蟹。
Hey, I got my filth back.
嘿，我把我的脏东西拿回来了。
Not for long, Mr. Stinky Shorts.
不会太久，臭短裤先生。
You won't have your filth
once I use this on you.
你不会有你的污秽
一旦我对你使用这个。
No, not soap.
不，不是肥皂。
You wouldn't dare.
你不敢。
Try me.
试试我吧。
Stay back.
退后一步。
I'll do it.
我会做的。
It's too late for that.
已经太晚了。
My beautiful filth.
我美丽的污秽。
It's gone.
它消失了。
I'm squeaky clean.
我很干净。
I'm covered in muck and scum.
我浑身都是淤泥和浮渣。
Man, to get my filth back,
I'll have to wallow
in mud forever.
伙计，为了拿回我的污秽，
我将不得不沉迷
永远在泥里。
It'll take weeks
for me to get clean.
这需要几周的时间
让我变得干净。
I'll need 20 baths a day.
我每天需要洗20次澡。
Slather toe jam on my armpits.
在我的腋窝上涂抹厚厚的脚趾果酱。
I'll have to disinfect
my eyeballs.
我得消毒
我的眼球。
Smear slime on my teeth.
把粘液涂在我的牙齿上。
And dry clean my uvula.
并干洗我的悬雍垂。
All right!
好的！
Now that I'm filthy, I can spend
all day getting clean.
现在我脏了，我可以花
一整天都变得干净起来。
And since I'm clean,
I can get even filthier.
而且因为我很干净，
我还可以变得更肮脏。
Thanks, SpongeBob.
谢谢，海绵宝宝。
No, Patrick, thank you.
不，帕特里克，谢谢你。
You're my best friend ever.
你是我最好的朋友。
Man: Hey, what's going on here?
男：嘿，这是怎么回事？
This battle isn't over
until we have a winner.
这场战斗还没有结束
直到我们分出胜负。
Fret not, my friend,
for I have learned the truth.
别担心，我的朋友，
因为我已经了解了真相。
It matters not whether
one is dirty or clean
是否重要并不重要
一个是脏的还是干净的
for can cleanliness exist
without filthiness?
清洁度是否存在
没有肮脏？
And would we know filthiness
without cleanliness?
我们会知道肮脏吗
没有清洁度？
We must not reenact
the history that divides us.
我们绝不能重蹈覆辙
分裂我们的历史。
Rather, we must embrace
that which draws us together.
相反，我们必须拥抱
使我们走到一起的东西。
All must be free
to choose their own path.
一切必须免费
选择自己的道路。
Right, friend Patrick?
对吧，帕特里克朋友？
Squeaky clean.
干干净净。
Squeaky, it's squeaky.
吱吱作响，真是吱吱作响。
Mm-hm.
嗯嗯。
He has embraced the truth.
他已经接受了真理。
Wow.
哇。
I think the little yellow guy
has taught us a valuable lesson.
我觉得小黄人
给我们上了宝贵的一课。
And what is that, my son?
那是什么，我的儿子？
That reenacting battles
is really lame.
那些重演的战斗
真是蹩脚。
Come on, guys.
来吧，伙计们。
Let's play something more manly,
like football.
玩点更有男人味的吧
就像足球一样。
Or hockey.
或者曲棍球。
Or knitting fluffy sweaters.
或者编织蓬松的毛衣。
Yeah!
是的！
Come, Patrick.
来吧，帕特里克。
My work here is done.
我这里的工作已经完成了。